taxtim.com 2018-10-04

# Privacy policy | TaxTim SA

## Updated 31 October 2017

_This privacy statement forms part of Taxtim's website terms and conditions. If you do not agree with any term of this privacy statement, you must cease your access of this website immediately._

**1\. Definitions and Interpretation**

1.1. "TaxTim" is the product of Human Robot (Pty) Ltd. 

1.2. "Personal Information" means information relating to an identifiable, living, natural person and where it is applicable, identifiable, existing juristic person, including all information as defined in the [Protection of Personal Information Act 4 of 2013](https://www.gov.za/documents/protection-personal-information-act) (POPI). 

1.3. "Processing" means the creation, generation, communication, storage, destruction of personal information as more fully defined in the Protection of Personal Information Act 4 of 2013. 

1.4. "You" or the "user" means any person who accesses and browses this website for any purpose. 

1.5. "Website" means the website of TaxTim at URL www.taxtim.com or such other URL as may chosen from time to time. 

**2\. Status and Amendments**

2.1. TaxTim respects your privacy. This privacy policy statement sets out TaxTim's information gathering and dissemination practices in respect of the Website. 

2.2. This Privacy Policy governs the processing of personal information provided to TaxTim through your use of the Website. 

2.3. Please note that, due to legal and other developments, TaxTim may amend these terms and conditions from time to time. The version of the terms and conditions effective for this Privacy Policy are indicated by the effective date incorporated in the title of this Privacy Policy. It is your duty to remain appraised of the current version of this Privacy Policy. The date indicated in the heading of this Privacy Policy is the effective date that governs the browsing and use of this Privacy Policy from that date until the next revision of this Privacy Policy becomes effective. 

2.4. By continuing to browse or use this Privacy Statement after a revised Privacy Policy becomes effective constitutes your agreement to observe this Privacy Policy as may be revised. 

**3\. Processing of Personal Information**

3.1. By providing your personal information to TaxTim you acknowledge that it has been collected directly from you and consent to its processing by TaxTim. 

3.2. Where you submit Personal Information (such as name, address, telephone number and email address) via the website (e.g. through completing any online form) the following principles are observed in the processing of that information: 

3.2.1. TaxTim will only collect personal information for a purpose consistent with the purpose for which it is required. The specific purpose for which information is collected will be apparent from the context in which it is requested. 

3.2.2. TaxTim will only process personal information in a manner that is adequate, relevant and not excessive in the context of the purpose for which it is processed. 

3.2.3. Personal information will only be processed for a purpose compatible with that for which it was collected, unless you have agreed to an alternative purpose in writing or TaxTim is permitted in terms of national legislation of general application dealing primarily with the protection of personal information. 

3.2.4. TaxTim will keep records of all tax information collected and the specific purpose for which it was collected for a period of 5 (five) years from the date on which it was used for its intended purposes as per the appropriate legislation. 

3.2.5. TaxTim will not disclose any personal information relating to you to any third party unless your prior written agreement is obtained or TaxTim is required to do so by law. 

3.2.6. If personal information is released with your consent TaxTim will retain a record of the information released, the third party to which it was released, the reason for the release and the date of release, for a period of 1 (one) year from the date on which it was last used. 

3.2.7. TaxTim will destroy or delete any personal information that is no longer needed by TaxTim for the purpose it was initially collected, or subsequently processed. 

3.2.8. We use your information, including any PII, to fulfill any other purposes for which you provide your information, for any other purpose as described to you at the time your information is collected or for which your consent is given or for any other purpose in our sole judgment to improve or enhance our user's website experience or to improve our operations and obligations. 

3.2.9. The appropriate method(s) for accessing your information, if any, will depend on which of our websites and services you have visited or used. Depending on the website and service, you may have the ability to view or edit some of your information online, by logging into the website and visiting your account profile page. If you remove information from your user profile, it may stay in backups on our servers for a period before being completely removed. Once deleted, your account is gone and cannot be restored. 

3.2.10 Content generated by the public, such as help desk questions & Q&A posts won't be deleted. It is possible that all this posted content may be changed to attributed by 'Anonymous' user. 

3.3. Note that, as permitted by the Electronic Communications and Transactions Act 25 of 2002, TaxTim may use personal information collected to compile profiles for statistical purposes. No information contained in the profiles or statistics will be able to be linked to any specific user. 

**4\. Collection of anonymous data**

4.1. TaxTim may use standard technology to collect information about the use of this website. This technology is not able to identify individual users but simply allows TaxTim to collect statistics. 

4.3. TaxTim may utilise temporary or session cookies to keep track of users' browsing habits. A cookie is a small file that is placed on your hard drive in order to keep a record of your interaction with this website and facilitate user convenience. 

4.3.1. Cookies by themselves will not be used to identify users personally but may be used to compile de-identified statistics relating to use of services offered or to provide TaxTim with feedback on the performance of this website. 

4.3.2. The following classes of information may be collected in respect of users who have enabled cookies: 

4.3.2.1. The browser software used;  
4.3.2.2. IP address;  
4.3.2.3. Date and time of activities while visiting the website;  
4.2.2.4. URLs of internal pages visited; and  
4.2.2.5. referrers. 

4.3. If you do not wish cookies to be employed to customize your interaction with this website it is possible to alter the manner in which your browser handles cookies. Please note that, if this is done, certain services on this website may not be available. 

4.3 This website uses the Google AdWords remarketing service to advertise on third party websites (including Google) to previous visitors to our site. It could mean that we advertise to previous visitors who haven't completed a task on our site, for example using the contact form to make an enquiry. This could be in the form of an advertisement on the Google search results page, or a site in the Google Display Network. Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on someone's past visits to the TaxTim website. Of course, any data collected will be used in accordance with our own privacy policy and Google's privacy policy. 

You can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Preferences page, and if you want to you can opt out of interest-based advertising entirely by cookie settings or permanently using a browser plugin. 

**5\. Security**

5.1. TaxTim takes reasonable measures to ensure the security and integrity of information submitted to or collected by this website, but cannot under any circumstances be held liable for any loss or other damage sustained by you as a result of unlawful access to or dissemination of any personal information by a third party. 

**6\. Links to other websites**

6.1. TaxTim has no control over and accepts no responsibility for the privacy practices of any third party websites to which hyperlinks may have been provided and TaxTim strongly recommends that you review the privacy policy of any website you visit before using it further. 

**7\. Queries**

7.1. If you have any queries about this privacy policy please contact us by emailing evan@taxtim.com.
